Educational Technology Services Records UA245
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
- Great Courses, 2014 -- 2017; UA245.001; 626 Digital Object(s); 1 Web sites
  - Notes to Philosophy 167: Class 4 -- Kepler's Planetary System and the Rudolphine Tables -- Part 7., 2014-09-23; gc.phil167.222
    Synopsis: Epitome Astronomiae Copernicanae (1618-1621) - Tabulae Rudolphinae: The Culmination (1627) Generally corresponds to the video segment: Class 4, Part 7.
  - Notes to Philosophy 167: Class 4 -- Kepler's Planetary System and the Rudolphine Tables -- Part 8., 2014-09-23; gc.phil167.223
    Synopsis: Tabulae Rudolphinae: The Culmination (1627) -- Some Philosophic Issues Concerning Kepler's "Laws": Kepler's Substantive Legacy: the Generalizations. Generally corresponds to the video segment: Class 4, Part 8.
  - Notes to Philosophy 167: Class 4 -- Kepler's Planetary System and the Rudolphine Tables -- Part 9 - Part 13., 2014-09-23; gc.phil167.224
    Synopsis: Some Philosophic Issues Concerning Kepler's "Laws": Kepler's Substantive Legacy: the Generalizations -- Some Advances in Turning Data into Evidence -- Accidental Versus Nomological Generalizations: Projectability -- A Complication: Exact Versus Approximate "Laws" -- Further Complications: Range and Qualifications -- Questions to Ask About Kepler's Generalizations -- An Examination of the Evidence for Kepler's "Laws": The Precise Statement of Kepler's Generalizations. Generally corresponds to the video segment: Class 4, Part 9 - 13.
  - Notes to Philosophy 167: Class 4 -- Kepler's Planetary System and the Rudolphine Tables -- Part 14., 2014-09-23; gc.phil167.225
    Synopsis: An Examination of the Evidence for Kepler's "Laws": The Precise Statement of Kepler's Generalizations -- The Evidence in 1630 for the Ellipse and Area "Laws" -- The Evidence in 1630 for the 3/2 Power "Law" -- Evidence that the "Laws" are Laws: Kepler's Approach -- Kepler's Approach to the Underlying Physics -- Illustrate Via the "Physics" for Keplerian Motion -- The Empirical Limitations of Kepler's Physics -- Kepler's Methodological Legacy: Some Final Remarks: Kepler's Conception of "Scientific" Astronomy -- Some Residual Problems Facing Kepler in 1630 -- Issues Raised on His Conception by These Problems. Generally corresponds to the video segment: Class 4, Part 14.
  - Notes to Philosophy 167: Class 4 -- Kepler's Planetary System and the Rudolphine Tables -- Part 15., 2014-09-23; gc.phil167.226
    Synopsis: An Examination of the Evidence for Kepler's "Laws": The Precise Statement of Kepler's Generalizations -- The Evidence in 1630 for the Ellipse and Area "Laws" -- The Evidence in 1630 for the 3/2 Power "Law" -- Evidence that the "Laws" are Laws: Kepler's Approach -- Kepler's Approach to the Underlying Physics -- Illustrate Via the "Physics" for Keplerian Motion -- The Empirical Limitations of Kepler's Physics -- Kepler's Methodological Legacy: Some Final Remarks: Kepler's Conception of "Scientific" Astronomy -- Some Residual Problems Facing Kepler in 1630 -- Issues Raised on His Conception by These Problems. Generally corresponds to the video segment: Class 4, Part 15.
  - Notes to Philosophy 167: Class 4 -- Kepler's Planetary System and the Rudolphine Tables -- Part 16., 2014-09-23; gc.phil167.227
    Synopsis: An Examination of the Evidence for Kepler's "Laws": The Precise Statement of Kepler's Generalizations -- The Evidence in 1630 for the Ellipse and Area "Laws" -- The Evidence in 1630 for the 3/2 Power "Law" -- Evidence that the "Laws" are Laws: Kepler's Approach -- Kepler's Approach to the Underlying Physics -- Illustrate Via the "Physics" for Keplerian Motion -- The Empirical Limitations of Kepler's Physics -- Kepler's Methodological Legacy: Some Final Remarks: Kepler's Conception of "Scientific" Astronomy -- Some Residual Problems Facing Kepler in 1630 -- Issues Raised on His Conception by These Problems. Generally corresponds to the video segment: Class 4, Part 16.
  - Notes to Philosophy 167: Class 4 -- Kepler's Planetary System and the Rudolphine Tables -- Part 17., 2014-09-23; gc.phil167.228
    Synopsis: An Examination of the Evidence for Kepler's "Laws": The Precise Statement of Kepler's Generalizations -- The Evidence in 1630 for the Ellipse and Area "Laws" -- The Evidence in 1630 for the 3/2 Power "Law" -- Evidence that the "Laws" are Laws: Kepler's Approach -- Kepler's Approach to the Underlying Physics -- Illustrate Via the "Physics" for Keplerian Motion -- The Empirical Limitations of Kepler's Physics -- Kepler's Methodological Legacy: Some Final Remarks: Kepler's Conception of "Scientific" Astronomy -- Some Residual Problems Facing Kepler in 1630 -- Issues Raised on His Conception by These Problems -- Generally corresponds to the video segment: Class 4, Part 17.
  - Notes to Philosophy 167: Class 5 -- Other Developments in Astronomy from 1609 to 1642 -- Complete., 2014-09-30; gc.phil167.334
    Synopsis: Introduction: Galileo's Place in 17th Century Science -- Galileo's Contributions to Astronomy, 1609-1633 -- Assimilation of the Two Revolutions in Astronomy from 1630-1642 -- The State of Astronomy as of Christmas Day, 1642 -- Select sources. Section: Class 5, Complete.
  - Notes to Philosophy 167: Class 5 -- Other Developments in Astronomy from 1609 to 1642 -- Part 1., 2014-09-30; gc.phil167.335
    Synopsis: Introduction: Galileo's Place in 17th Century Science -- Galileo Galilei: A Biographical Sketch Generally corresponds to the video segment: Class 5, Part 1.
  - Notes to Philosophy 167: Class 5 -- Other Developments in Astronomy from 1609 to 1642 -- Part 2., 2014-09-30; gc.phil167.336
    Synopsis: Galileo Galilei: A Biographical Sketch -- Galileo Galilei: Some Personal Remarks -- Galileo's Contributions to Astronomy, 1609-1633. Generally corresponds to the video segment: Class 5, Part 2.
  - Notes to Philosophy 167: Class 5 -- Other Developments in Astronomy from 1609 to 1642 -- Part 3., 2014-09-30; gc.phil167.337
    Synopsis: Galileo Galilei: A Biographical Sketch -- Galileo Galilei: Some Personal Remarks -- Galileo's Contributions to Astronomy, 1609-1633. Generally corresponds to the video segment: Class 5, Part 3.
  - Notes to Philosophy 167: Class 5 -- Other Developments in Astronomy from 1609 to 1642 -- Part 4., 2014-09-30; gc.phil167.338
    Synopsis: Galileo's Contributions to Astronomy, 1609-1633:Sidereus Nuncius -- The First Telescopic Results (1610) Generally corresponds to the video segment: Class 5, Part 4.
  - Notes to Philosophy 167: Class 5 -- Other Developments in Astronomy from 1609 to 1642 -- Part 5., 2014-09-30; gc.phil167.339
    Synopsis: Galileo's Telescopes: Design and Limitations -- Further Telescopic Discoveries: 1610-1620 Generally corresponds to the video segment: Class 5, Part 5.
  - Notes to Philosophy 167: Class 5 -- Other Developments in Astronomy from 1609 to 1642 -- Part 6., 2014-09-30; gc.phil167.340
    Synopsis: Further Telescopic Discoveries: 1610-1620 -- Some Background to Galileo's Dialogue Generally corresponds to the video segment: Class 5, Part 6.
  - Notes to Philosophy 167: Class 5 -- Other Developments in Astronomy from 1609 to 1642 -- Part 7., 2014-09-30; gc.phil167.341
    Synopsis: Some Background to Galileo's Dialogue Generally corresponds to the video segment: Class 5, Part 7.
  - Notes to Philosophy 167: Class 5 -- Other Developments in Astronomy from 1609 to 1642 -- Part 8., 2014-09-30; gc.phil167.342
    Synopsis: Dialogue Concerning the Two Chief World Systems (1632) Generally corresponds to the video segment: Class 5, Part 8.
  - Notes to Philosophy 167: Class 5 -- Other Developments in Astronomy from 1609 to 1642 -- Part 9., 2014-09-30; gc.phil167.343
    Synopsis: Dialogue Concerning the Two Chief World Systems (1632) -- The Copernican System of the Dialogue, Versus Kepler's -- Galileo's Theory of the Tides, Versus Kepler's Theory -- Galileo's Trial and Recantation (1633) Generally corresponds to the video segment: Class 5, Part 9.
  - Notes to Philosophy 167: Class 5 -- Other Developments in Astronomy from 1609 to 1642 -- Part 10 - Part 11., 2014-09-30; gc.phil167.344
    Synopsis: Galileo's Trial and Recantation (1633) -- The State of "Predictive Astronomy" in 1630 Generally corresponds to the video segment: Class 5, Part 10 - 11.
  - Notes to Philosophy 167: Class 5 -- Other Developments in Astronomy from 1609 to 1642 -- Part 12., 2014-09-30; gc.phil167.345
    Synopsis: The State of "Predictive Astronomy" in 1630 -- The Transit of Mercury in 1631 -- Impact of the Transit on Predictive Astronomy -- The Issue of Planetary Dimensions -- The Problem of the Solar Parallax. Generally corresponds to the video segment: Class 5, Part 12.
  - Notes to Philosophy 167: Class 5 -- Other Developments in Astronomy from 1609 to 1642 -- Part 13., 2014-09-30; gc.phil167.346
    Synopsis: Horrocks on Venus: Venus in sole visa (1662) -- Horrocks and the Problem of the Moon Generally corresponds to the video segment: Class 5, Part 13.
  - Notes to Philosophy 167: Class 5 -- Other Developments in Astronomy from 1609 to 1642 -- Part 14., 2014-09-30; gc.phil167.347
    Synopsis: Horrocks and the Problem of the Moon -- Telescopic Innovations and their Impact Generally corresponds to the video segment: Class 5, Part 14.
  - Notes to Philosophy 167: Class 5 -- Other Developments in Astronomy from 1609 to 1642 -- Part 15., 2014-09-30; gc.phil167.348
    Synopsis: The "Copernican Revolution" -- 100 Years -- Major Open Questions: Evidential Problems -- The Changing Conception of the Science -- Select Sources Generally corresponds to the video segment: Class 5, Part 15.
  - Notes to Philosophy 167: Class 6 -- Galileo's Two New Sciences: Local Natural Motion -- Complete., 2014-10-7; gc.phil167.349
    Synopsis: Local Motion Versus Celestial Motion: The Problem -- "The Third Day": Some Conceptual Obstacles -- "The Third Day": Evidential Difficulties -- Galileo's Contribution to Science: Some Issues -- Select sources. Section: Class 6, Complete.
  - Notes to Philosophy 167: Class 6 -- Galileo's Two New Sciences: Local Natural Motion -- Part 1 - Part 3., 2014-10-7; gc.phil167.350
    Synopsis: Astronomy Versus the "Science" of Motion: 1638 -- The Fundamental Empirical Problems Contrasted. Generally corresponds to the video segment: Class 6, Part 1 - 3.
  - Notes to Philosophy 167: Class 6 -- Galileo's Two New Sciences: Local Natural Motion -- Part 4., 2014-10-7; gc.phil167.351
    Synopsis: The Fundamental Empirical Problems Contrasted -- A Further Complication: Pertinent Variables -- Galileo's Approach: An "Idealized" Science. Generally corresponds to the video segment: Class 6, Part 4.
  - Notes to Philosophy 167: Class 6 -- Galileo's Two New Sciences: Local Natural Motion -- Part 5., 2014-10-7; gc.phil167.352
    Synopsis: A Further Complication: Pertinent Variables -- Galileo's Approach: An "Idealized" Science. Generally corresponds to the video segment: Class 6, Part 5.
  - Notes to Philosophy 167: Class 6 -- Galileo's Two New Sciences: Local Natural Motion -- Part 6 - Part 7., 2014-10-7; gc.phil167.353
    Synopsis: Galileo's Approach: An "Idealized" Science -- The Evidential Challenge Facing the Science -- Galileo's Conceptualization of Motion. Generally corresponds to the video segment: Class 6, Part 6 -7.
  - Notes to Philosophy 167: Class 6 -- Galileo's Two New Sciences: Local Natural Motion -- Part 8., 2014-10-7; gc.phil167.354
    Synopsis: Galileo's Conceptualization of Motion -- Abrupt Versus Continuous Change in Speed. Generally corresponds to the video segment: Class 6, Part 8.
  - Notes to Philosophy 167: Class 6 -- Galileo's Two New Sciences: Local Natural Motion -- Part 9., 2014-10-7; gc.phil167.355
    Synopsis: Abrupt Versus Continuous Change in Speed -- Motion Versus Rest: Impetus and Momenta -- Alternative Concepts of Uniform Acceleration. Generally corresponds to the video segment: Class 6, Part 9.
  - Notes to Philosophy 167: Class 6 -- Galileo's Two New Sciences: Local Natural Motion -- Part 10., 2014-10-7; gc.phil167.356
    Synopsis: Motion Versus Rest: Impetus and Momenta -- Alternative Concepts of Uniform Acceleration -- A Fundamental Result: The Mean Speed Theorem. Generally corresponds to the video segment: Class 6, Part 10.
  - Notes to Philosophy 167: Class 6 -- Galileo's Two New Sciences: Local Natural Motion -- Part 11., 2014-10-7; gc.phil167.357
    Synopsis: A Fundamental Result: The Mean Speed Theorem -- The Postulate: Empirical Motivation and Grounds -- Proposition II and the 1,3,5,... Pattern -- The Inclined Plane Experiment in the "Third Day". Generally corresponds to the video segment: Class 6, Part 11.
  - Notes to Philosophy 167: Class 6 -- Galileo's Two New Sciences: Local Natural Motion -- Part 12., 2014-10-7; gc.phil167.358
    Synopsis: A Fundamental Result: The Mean Speed Theorem -- The Postulate: Empirical Motivation and Grounds -- Proposition II and the 1,3,5,... Pattern.. Generally corresponds to the video segment: Class 6, Part 12.
  - Notes to Philosophy 167: Class 6 -- Galileo's Two New Sciences: Local Natural Motion -- Part 13., 2014-10-7; gc.phil167.359
    Synopsis: The Inclined Plane Experiment in the "Third Day" -- The Earlier Inclined Plane Experiment -- Drake (Galileo at Work). Generally corresponds to the video segment: Class 6, Part 13.
  - Notes to Philosophy 167: Class 6 -- Galileo's Two New Sciences: Local Natural Motion -- Part 14., 2014-10-7; gc.phil167.360
    Synopsis: The Earlier Inclined Plane Experiment -- Drake (Galileo at Work) -- A Crucial Lacuna in the Evidential Argument -- The Effect of the Lacuna on Propositions III-VI -- Mersenne's Efforts and the Lacuna: 1633-1647. Generally corresponds to the video segment: Class 6, Part 14.
  - Notes to Philosophy 167: Class 6 -- Galileo's Two New Sciences: Local Natural Motion -- Part 15., 2014-10-7; gc.phil167.361
    Synopsis: Mersenne's Efforts and the Lacuna: 1633-1647 -- Riccioli's Efforts and the Lacuna: 1640-1651 -- The Evidential Difficulties as of 1651: A Recap. Generally corresponds to the video segment: Class 6, Part 15.
  - Notes to Philosophy 167: Class 6 -- Galileo's Two New Sciences: Local Natural Motion -- Part 16., 2014-10-7; gc.phil167.362
    Synopsis: The Evidential Difficulties as of 1651: A Recap -- Galileo's Place in the History of Mechanics -- Galileo's Contribution to Scientific Method -- Philosophical Disputes Over Two New Sciences -- Issues We Must Face and Our Approach to Them -- Select Sources. Generally corresponds to the video segment: Class 6, Part 16.
  - Notes to Philosophy 167: Class 7 -- Galileo's Two New Sciences: Projectile Motion -- Complete., 2014-10-14; gc.phil167.363
    Synopsis: Issues Raised by Galileo's Two New Sciences -- "The Third Day": Ramified Mathematical Development -- "The Fourth Day": Conceptual Development of the Theory -- "The Fourth Day": The Theory of Projectile Motion -- Remarks on Galileo's Contribution to Modern Science. Section: Class 7, Complete.
  - Notes to Philosophy 167: Class 7 -- Galileo's Two New Sciences: Projectile Motion -- Part 1., 2014-10-14; gc.phil167.364
    Synopsis: The Issues and Controversies Reviewed -- Evidential Status of the "Law" of Free Fall. Generally corresponds to the video segment: Class 7, Part 1.
  - Notes to Philosophy 167: Class 7 -- Galileo's Two New Sciences: Projectile Motion -- Part 2., 2014-10-14; gc.phil167.365
    Synopsis: Propositions VII-XXXVIII: The Mathematical Theory -- A Key Result: "Conversion" into Horizontal Motion -- Some Other Interesting (and Testable) Results. Generally corresponds to the video segment: Class 7, Part 2.
  - Notes to Philosophy 167: Class 7 -- Galileo's Two New Sciences: Projectile Motion -- Part 3., 2014-10-14; gc.phil167.366
    Synopsis: Some Other Interesting (and Testable) Results -- The Theory as a Question-Answering Device -- A Parabolic Path: The Basic Idea. Generally corresponds to the video segment: Class 7, Part 3.
  - Notes to Philosophy 167: Class 7 -- Galileo's Two New Sciences: Projectile Motion -- Part 4., 2014-10-14; gc.phil167.367
    Synopsis: A Parabolic Path: The Basic Idea -- A Problem: Local Versus Circular Motion. Generally corresponds to the video segment: Class 7, Part 4.
  - Notes to Philosophy 167: Class 7 -- Galileo's Two New Sciences: Projectile Motion -- Part 5., 2014-10-14; gc.phil167.368
    Synopsis: A Problem: Local Versus Circular Motion -- The Problem of Compound Impetus: Which Parabola. Generally corresponds to the video segment: Class 7, Part 5.
  - Notes to Philosophy 167: Class 7 -- Galileo's Two New Sciences: Projectile Motion -- Part 6., 2014-10-14; gc.phil167.369
    Synopsis: The Problem of Compound Impetus: Which Parabola -- Galileo's Solution for Compound Impetus -- Galileo's Determination of the Parabola. Generally corresponds to the video segment: Class 7, Part 6.
  - Notes to Philosophy 167: Class 7 -- Galileo's Two New Sciences: Projectile Motion -- Part 7., 2014-10-14; gc.phil167.370
    Synopsis: Galileo's Determination of the Parabola -- The Significance of Galileo's Approach -- The Basic Claims Made by Galileo's Theory -- Mathematical Consequences of the Theory. Generally corresponds to the video segment: Class 7, Part 7.
  - Notes to Philosophy 167: Class 7 -- Galileo's Two New Sciences: Projectile Motion -- Part 8., 2014-10-14; gc.phil167.371
    Synopsis: Mathematical Consequences of the Theory -- The Form and Content of Galileo's Table. Generally corresponds to the video segment: Class 7, Part 8.
  - Notes to Philosophy 167: Class 7 -- Galileo's Two New Sciences: Projectile Motion -- Part 9., 2014-10-14; gc.phil167.372
    Synopsis: The Form and Content of Galileo's Table -- "Real World" Deviations from the Theory -- Practical and Scientific Concerns Contrasted -- Galileo's Suppressed "Ski-Jump" Experiment. Generally corresponds to the video segment: Class 7, Part 9.
  - Notes to Philosophy 167: Class 7 -- Galileo's Two New Sciences: Projectile Motion -- Part 10 - Part 11., 2014-10-14; gc.phil167.373
    Synopsis: Galileo's Suppressed "Ski-Jump" Experiment. Generally corresponds to the video segment: Class 7, Part 10 - 11.
  - Notes to Philosophy 167: Class 7 -- Galileo's Two New Sciences: Projectile Motion -- Part 12., 2014-10-14; gc.phil167.374
    Synopsis: Galileo's "Laws" at the End of "The Fourth Day" -- Remarks on Galileo's Contribution to Modern Science: Observation, Theory, and Experiment -- The Theory of Local Motion: Scope and Content -- Galileo's Research in its Historical Context -- Galilean Conceptions of Empirical Science -- A Conjecture About How Galileo Proceeded. Generally corresponds to the video segment: Class 7, Part 12.
  - Notes to Philosophy 167: Class 8 -- Descartes' Principia: Laws of Motion -- Complete., 2014-10-21; gc.phil167.242
    Synopsis: Kepler and Galileo: The Second Post-Copernican Generation -- Descartes: The Third Post-Copernican Generation -- Descartes' "Mechanical Philosophy" -- Descartes' Laws of Motion -- Descartes' Rules of Perfectly Elastic Impact. Section: Class 8, Complete.
  - Notes to Philosophy 167: Class 8 -- Descartes' Principia: Laws of Motion -- Part 1., 2014-10-21; gc.phil167.243
    Synopsis: The Legacy of Two New Sciences -- Kepler and Galileo: Some Contrasts -- In Pursuit of a Truly Empirical Science -- Generally corresponds to the video segment: Class 8, Part 1.
  - Notes to Philosophy 167: Class 8 -- Descartes' Principia: Laws of Motion -- Part 2., 2014-10-21; gc.phil167.244
    Synopsis: Descartes: A Biographical Sketch -- Descartes' Intellectual Mission. Generally corresponds to the video segment: Class 8, Part 2.
  - Notes to Philosophy 167: Class 8 -- Descartes' Principia: Laws of Motion -- Part 3 - Part 4., 2014-10-21; gc.phil167.245
    Synopsis: Descartes: A Biographical Sketch -- Descartes' Intellectual Mission. Generally corresponds to the video segment: Class 8, Part 3 - 4.
  - Notes to Philosophy 167: Class 8 -- Descartes' Principia: Laws of Motion -- Part 5 - Part 6., 2014-10-21; gc.phil167.246
    Synopsis: Descartes' Intellectual Mission -- The Scope and Goals of Cartesian Science -- The Historical Significance of Cartesian Science -- The Mechanical Philosophy: Two Schools -- Descartes on the Vacuum and Atomism -- The Plenist World View, Versus Ours -- Descartes on Magnetic Phenomena. Generally corresponds to the video segment: Class 8, Part 5 - 6.
  - Notes to Philosophy 167: Class 8 -- Descartes' Principia: Laws of Motion -- Part 7., 2014-10-21; gc.phil167.247
    Synopsis: The Mechanical Philosophy: Descartes on Magnetic Phenomena -- Descartes on Gravity and Weight -- Circulation and Conservation of Motion. Generally corresponds to the video segment: Class 8, Part 7.
  - Notes to Philosophy 167: Class 8 -- Descartes' Principia: Laws of Motion -- Part 8., 2014-10-21; gc.phil167.248
    Synopsis: Circulation and Conservation of Motion -- The First Law of Motion (i.e. Nature) Generally corresponds to the video segment: Class 8, Part 8.
  - Notes to Philosophy 167: Class 8 -- Descartes' Principia: Laws of Motion -- Part 9., 2014-10-21; gc.phil167.249
    Synopsis: The First Law of Motion (i.e. Nature) -- The Second Law of Motion: Circular Motion -- Comments on the Principle of "Inertia" Generally corresponds to the video segment: Class 8, Part 9.
  - Notes to Philosophy 167: Class 8 -- Descartes' Principia: Laws of Motion -- Part 10., 2014-10-21; gc.phil167.250
    Synopsis: Comments on the Principle of "Inertia" -- Some Issues with the Principle of Inertia -- The Third Law of Motion. Generally corresponds to the video segment: Class 8, Part 10.
  - Notes to Philosophy 167: Class 8 -- Descartes' Principia: Laws of Motion -- Part 11., 2014-10-21; gc.phil167.251
    Synopsis: The Third Law of Motion -- The Concept of a Law of Nature -- Change of Motion and the Concept of Force. Generally corresponds to the video segment: Class 8, Part 11.
  - Notes to Philosophy 167: Class 8 -- Descartes' Principia: Laws of Motion -- Part 12., 2014-10-21; gc.phil167.252
    Synopsis: Change of Motion and the Concept of Force -- The Rules for Change of Motion After Impact -- Empirical Problems: Descartes' Defense. Generally corresponds to the video segment: Class 8, Part 12.
  - Notes to Philosophy 167: Class 8 -- Descartes' Principia: Laws of Motion -- Part 13., 2014-10-21; gc.phil167.253
    Synopsis: Empirical Problems: Descartes' Defense -- Relativity of Motion: "Internal" Problems. Generally corresponds to the video segment: Class 8, Part 13.
  - Notes to Philosophy 167: Class 8 -- Descartes' Principia: Laws of Motion -- Part 14., 2014-10-21; gc.phil167.254
    Synopsis: Relativity of Motion: "Internal" Problems -- Descartes on "True" Motion. Generally corresponds to the video segment: Class 8, Part 14.
  - Notes to Philosophy 167: Class 9 -- Descartes' Principia: The Vortex Theory of the Heavens -- Complete., 2014-10-28; gc.phil167.255
    Synopsis: The Cartesian "Shift" of Emphasis in Science -- The Vortex Theory of the Heavens -- Ramifications of the Vortex Theory -- Cartesian Conceptions of Empirical Science. Section: Class 1, Complete.
  - Notes to Philosophy 167: Class 9 -- Descartes' Principia: The Vortex Theory of the Heavens -- Part 1., 2014-10-28; gc.phil167.256
    Synopsis: Understanding as One of the Goals of Science -- The Focus on the Foundations of Science -- Comprehensive Versus Piecemeal Science -- The Legacy of Descartes' Mechanics -- The Problem Addressed by the Vortex Theory. Generally corresponds to the video segment: Class 1, Part 1.
  - Notes to Philosophy 167: Class 9 -- Descartes' Principia: The Vortex Theory of the Heavens -- Part 2., 2014-10-28; gc.phil167.257